### Our privacy policy

The Rothschild Foundation is a registered charity and a company limited by guarantee. The work of the Foundation has two distinct remits: as an operating charity responsible for the care and management of Waddesdon Manor on behalf of the National Trust and undertaking more general philanthropic activity in support of the arts and heritage, the environment, education, and social welfare by awarding grants and convening, fostering dialogue and debate.

At Waddesdon we take the security and privacy of data very seriously. Our security measures are continuously maintained and adhered to along with our privacy policy below. The Rothschild Foundation, Waddesdon Manor, and its subsidiary companies makes every effort to comply with the principles of the UK General Data Protection Regulations (UK GDPR) and the Data Protection Act (DPA) 2018.

The Rothschild Foundation is the data controller, and our registered address is The Rothschild Foundation, Windmill Hill, Silk Street, Waddesdon, Buckinghamshire HP18 0JZ.

The Rothschild Foundation respects your privacy and will take all steps to protect the personal information we hold about you.

### Visitors

We collect information about you when you register with us, book a visit, event, or place an order via the website or telephone. We also collect information when you voluntarily sign up for our newsletter, complete customer surveys, provide feedback, participate in competitions, or apply for a job or volunteer role with us. Website information is collected using cookies.

**What information do we collect about you?**

Personal information such as your name, address, telephone number, date of birth, age, your photo and email address, car registration and any other information that you provide to us freely when you register with us either in person or online when you purchase our tickets, register for free Waddesdon Wi-Fi, apply for your Annual Pass, provide feedback or when you send us an email.

We will only collect children’s data which is provided and consented by the parent or someone with parental responsibility.

**How will we use the information about you?**

We collect information about you to process your orders and bookings, manage your account, process your applications and, if you agree, to email you about other products, services, and promotions we think may be of interest to you.

Personal information collected while making group bookings, events, weddings, or conferences. This information is used to administer the event and your account only. You will not receive any marketing emails unless you subscribe to our newsletter.

We use the information collected from the website to improve the way we deliver information online.

The use of your information may involve sharing the information with employees, contractors, agents, and professional advisors of Waddesdon Manor (Rothschild Foundation), the National Trust, fraud prevention agencies, and other carefully selected organisations. Written agreement exists between Waddesdon Manor (Rothschild Foundation) and such parties that there must be no further disclosure of such personal data or usage for direct marketing by those organisations unless you consent.

### Suppliers

We hold information about our Suppliers where it is necessary for us to conduct our business activities and purchase supplies. We do not share our suppliers’ information with any third party unless previously agreed in advance. Suppliers include our contractors and subcontractors.

### Tenants

We collect information about you to manage your tenancy, manage your account, and process your applications. If you agree we may email you about other services we think might be of interest to you.

Tenanted properties are owned by a number of landlords, including the Rothschild Foundation and the Waddesdon Estate LLP, however all tenancies are managed by the Rothschild Foundation Property team. Our use of your information may involve sharing this with employees, contractors, agents and professional advisors of the Rothschild Foundation, Waddesdon Estate LLP, fraud prevention agencies, and other carefully selected organisations. Written agreement exists with such parties stating that there must be no further disclosure of such personal data or usage for direct marketing by those organisations unless you consent.

If you are interested in renting a property from Waddesdon we will hold your details on a prospective tenancy list to provide you with information about suitable properties when they become available.  You have a right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes or from giving your information to any third parties as detailed above.

### Grant applicants and recipients

We collect information about you when you register with us, contact us, or apply for a grant. We also collect information when you voluntarily sign up for our newsletter, complete customer surveys, provide feedback, or participate in competitions.

**How will we use the information about you?**

We may use such information to process your application(s), manage your account, and, if you agree, to email you about other grants or services we think may be of interest to you. We keep a record of applications to enable us to maintain records of your application history should you apply again, including assessment notes. In addition to application data, we will retain all personal data related to the administration or operation of the grant, including (not limited to): applicant name, email address and phone number.

We use the information collected from the website to improve the way we deliver information online.

The use of your information may involve sharing the information with employees, contractors, agents and professional advisors of Rothschild Foundation, fraud prevention agencies, and other carefully selected organisations. Written agreement exists between Rothschild Foundation and such parties that there must be no further disclosure of such personal data or usage for direct marketing by those organisations unless you consent.

**Personal data supplied by Grant applicants, and current or former grant recipients.**

We will only ask for as much information as we need to effectively consider a grant application, to manage an awarded grant, and to monitor its progress. By submitting an application, you are agreeing to us processing your data for these purposes and in the ways outlined in this section. Grant applications are saved within our grants database (Blackbaud Grantmaking), which is compliant with UK GDPR. The Blackbaud privacy policy can be viewed on the [Blackbaud website](https://www.blackbaud.co.uk/company/privacy-policy/europe).

**Data about what we fund.**

The Rothschild Foundation publishes limited information in its annual accounts which are submitted to Companies House and the Charity Commission. We also publish grants data on the 360Giving website under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, please visit the Creative Commons website.  Published information will include: the title and description of the funding, name of the recipient, date of the award, its duration and the amount awarded. We will not publish address details of individuals who are awarded funding except where these are also the registered addresses of organisations we fund.

We may also include information on funding awarded in presentations about our work or as case studies, with permission, on our website.

There may be times we share information with a third-party organisation, such as a charity or other funder who may contact us for a reference. Most information will be organisational and not personal, but at times personal data (for example the names of senior staff) may be included. This is a legitimate interest as it will improve funding to the sectors, we offer grants too.

### Job applicants, current and former employees

When individuals apply to work with us, we only use the information they supply to process their application.

Once a person has taken up employment with us, we create a staff file relating to their employment. This information is only used for purposes directly relevant to that person’s employment.

Our staff GDPR Data Protection Policy is available to all our current employees via HR or on the intranet.

### Volunteers

When individuals apply to volunteer with us, we only use the information they supply to process their application.

Once their application has been accepted, we manage their volunteering through the National Trust Volunteering systems – MyVolunteering and Your Volunteering. All personal information will only be used to manage their volunteer role, rotas, tasks, and training. Emergency contact details will only be used in the event of an emergency.

### CCTV

We operate CCTV at various locations around the Waddesdon estate, especially at the entrances to the site. This is required for the prevention and detection of crime and for protecting the safety of staff, tenants, and visitors. It will not be used for other purposes. We have a CCTV Code of Practice which sets out how we use CCTV and we conduct an annual review of our use of CCTV. The recorded images are programmed to be deleted after a reasonable time.

We use Auto Number Plate Recognition (ANPR) technology for the security and protection of our site. Employees and regular contractors can ask for their details to be added to the gate system. Other vehicles passing the gates are not recorded.

### How long do we retain your information?

**Customers**

For a reasonable period, after you have stopped being an active customer. After this time, the data we hold will either be suppressed or deleted or retained providing you have asked us to do so. You have options to unsubscribe to our mailing list at any time.

**Suppliers**

For a reasonable period, after you have stopped being an active supplier. After this time, the data we will be held securely stored on our networks in accordance with our statutory obligations.

**Tenants**

For a reasonable period, after you have stopped being an active tenant. After this time, the data will be held securely stored on our networks in accordance with our statutory obligations.

**Job applicants, current and former employees**

Personal information about unsuccessful candidates will be held for up to one year after the recruitment exercise has been completed and will then be destroyed or deleted.

Once employment has ended, we will retain the file in accordance with our statutory obligations and the information will be stored on our secured networks.

### Your rights under GDPR

* Right to be informed – You have the right to ask for information we hold for you.  Please request for our Subject Access Procedure and a Subject Access Request form.
* Right to Rectification – The data we hold will be corrected when we are notified of any changes or errors.
* Right to be forgotten – Information we hold for you will no longer be processed if requested to do so.
* Right to complain to ICO (Information Commissioners’ Office)

We are happy to answer your queries or concerns regarding your data. Please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://rothschildfoundation.org.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

We may ask you to verify your identity before supplying the information. Acceptable forms of ID include:

* Photocard driver’s licence
* Passport

We want to make sure your personal information is accurate and up to date, you may ask us to correct or remove information you may think is inaccurate.

If subsequently, you make a data protection instruction to Waddesdon Manor (Rothschild Foundation) which contradicts a previous instruction (or instructions), then Waddesdon Manor (Rothschild Foundation) will follow your most recent instruction.

### Security

Waddesdon Manor (Rothschild Foundation) holds your personal data in accordance with the security provisions of the UK Data Protection legislation. We use industry standard Secure Server Software (SSL) for your transactions with us. It encrypts all your personal information, including credit card number, name, and address, so that it cannot be read as the information travels over the internet.

### Changes to this policy

We keep our privacy policy under regular review, and we will place any updates on this web page.

This privacy policy was last updated on: 18 April 2023
